

# **Profile**

My dream is to fulfil the task of changing lives through the technology I help to build. Any team that I have been fortunate to be apart of, has always had one or two indistinguishable qualities that have brought the best of myself and my colleagues: Professionalism and Communication. Creating lasting experiences for the end-user only comes to fruition though the lasting experiences shared with the team that's created them. I plan to build-on my young career with the golden foundations laid by great professionals and communicators.

# **Employment History**

### Junior Associate Software Engineer, Publicis Sapient, City of London

MARCH 2021 - SEPTEMBER 2022

### Responsibilities:

- Assisting the development manager with all aspects of software design and coding
- Attending, contributing and presenting updates during company development meetings, daily Stand-Ups with Junior Engineering team.
- Conducting Integration and Unit-Tests.
- Learning the code base (JavaScript, Typescript, React), improving my coding skills.
- Mentoring our Junior Software Engineers coming through the Publicis Sapient Apprenticeship Program (allied with Multiverse)

#### Apprentice - Junior Engineer, Multiverse & Publicis Sapient, City of London

MARCH 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Contribute to strategic discussions
- Develop and learn new techologies and methodologies
- Maintain systems and applications
- Learn how the team break down project requirements into smaller stories, ready for development.
- Work with other team members to actively identify blockers, or issues and actively attempt to remove them

#### **Event Security, SERVOCA, London**

FEBRUARY 2019 - MARCH 2020

#### Responsibilities:

- Help to provide a sense of protection for attendees and staff
- Maintaining order, including directing foot traffic, helping lost people, or assisting in disturbances.
- Regular reporting, as SERVOCA Security are responsible for reporting any suspicious activity to our supervisor.

# Cover Letter for Xander

As someone who has certainly not had the clearest path into Software Engineering, losing faith in my capabilities to grasp certain ideas or methods, constantly having to dig myself out of periods of low motivation; the blessing that I've been afforded was the people I've had around me during this journey. The teachers during my

#### **Details**

Shepherd's Bush United Kingdom +447494429917 joaojosecamba@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

British

DATE OF BIRTH

December 15th 1999

### Links

**GitHub** 

LinkedIn

### Skills

JavaScript

React Library

**NextJS Library** 

HTML & CSS

**Amazon Web Services** 

Apollo GraphQL

apprenticeship at Mutliverse stood as daunting figures, figures that I revered due to their vast knowledge, expertise and ease with communicating complex topics.

They were the same figures that I faithfully leaned on for confidence and advice during difficult times. What I valued was the opportunity to learn, the opportunity to fail, and the opportunity to prove myself in times when it seemed uncomfortable.

Xander's Training Academy, stood out to me as an opportunity to continue on the path of learning. The 9 Week training programme is something I'm excited to be apart of, I have a strong desire to dig deep and embrace the challenge of securing a Client placement, working alongside people who are on the same path as myself, early in their careers, looking to make a difference together.

# **Education**

**Gunnersbury Catholic School, London** 

SEPTEMBER 2011 - JULY 2016

**Gunnersbury Catholic School - Sixth Form, London** 

SEPTEMBER 2016 - JULY 2018

Achieved a BTEC Business Certification grade D\*D\*D\*

Business Management, University of Surrey, Guildford, Surrey

AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2019

## **Certifications**

**AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services** 

Software Developer Level 4, Institute for Apprenticeships & Technical Education

Microsoft Technology Associate: Introduction to Programming (JavaScript), Microsoft

GraphQL Developer - Associate, Apollo GraphQL

## Extra-curricular activities

Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu, Gracie Barra Fulham, London

JULY 2022 - PRESENT

Fitness, Kiss Gym, London

MAY 2022 - PRESENT